Hello, I'm Dr. Joshua Kassis, founder and chiropractor at the Balanced Chiropractic Centre in Yandina.
On behalf of our entire team, I'd like to welcome you to our practice.
The Balanced Chiropractic Centre opened its doors in 2023 after transforming what was once a local pharmacy into a modern, wellness-focused chiropractic centre.
Our vision was simple: to create a place where people and families could discover the true cause of their health concerns.
restore their health naturally and live life to the fullest potential.
Since opening, we've had the privilege of helping hundreds of people in our local community and we're excited to have the opportunity to meet you.
The purpose of this video is to help you understand what to expect during your first visit at our practice.
Whether this is your first time seeing a chiropractor
or you've had chiropractic care before, your first appointment is all about you.
We’ll take the time to understand your health history, your current concerns, your challenges and most importantly your health goals.
We believe that every person has a unique story, so we'll listen carefully before carrying out any examination.
Our goal is to determine exactly what's causing your problem and whether chiropractic care is the right fit for you.
If it is, we'll perform an assessment using our advanced technology including a state-of-the-art inflammation scanner
that will clearly and specifically show us the hotspots in your spine and body,
as well as convenient on-site digital x-rays which help us identify areas of stress and dysfunction within your body.
Having these tools under one roof allows us to gain a clear understanding of your body
to provide care that's tailored specifically to you.
People come to our practice for many different reasons.
Some are already experiencing symptoms such as neck pain, headaches, lower back issues, sciatica,
disc injuries, shoulder pain or even just poor posture.
Others are looking for answers after trying multiple treatments without any results.
We also care for families, children and people who simply want to optimise their health and wellbeing.
While many people initially visit us
because they're in pain, they stay because they experience the benefits of a healthier nerve system and a body that functions the way that it was designed to.
At the Balanced Chiropractic Centre, we focus on finding and correcting the underlying cause of dysfunction rather than simply masking symptoms.
We know your nerve system controls every function, including how well it heals.
Before you come in, I'd like you to think about two simple questions.
First one, are you as healthy as you want to be?
and the second,
if not,
what’s stopping you from getting there?
Again, I'm Dr. Josh and we look forward to meeting you, learning your story and helping you take the next step on your journey towards a much better health.